{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Poor data administration can lead to which of the following?", "opta": "A single definition of the same data entity", "optb": "Familiarity with existing data", "optc": "Missing data elements", "optd": "All of the above.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A traditional data administrator performs which of the following roles?", "opta": "Tune database performance", "optb": "Establish backup and recovery procedures", "optc": "Resolve data ownership issues", "optd": "Protect the security of the database.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If both data and database administration exist in an organization, the database administrator is responsible for which of the following?", "opta": "Data modeling", "optb": "Database design", "optc": "Metadata", "optd": "All of the above.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is part of an administrative policy to secure a database?", "opta": "Authentication policies", "optb": "Limiting particular areas within a building to only authorized people", "optc": "Ensure appropriate responses rates are in external maintenance agreements", "optd": "All of the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Backward recovery is which of the following?", "opta": "Where the before-images are applied to the database", "optb": "Where the after-images are applied to the database", "optc": "Where the after-images and before-images are applied to the database", "optd": "Switching to an existing copy of the database", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The transaction log includes which of the following?", "opta": "The before-image of a record", "optb": "The after-image of a record", "optc": "The before and after-image of a record", "optd": "The essential data of the record", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following could cause data to be unavailable?", "opta": "Data becoming lost or inaccurate", "optb": "The database server", "optc": "Planned database maintenance activities", "optd": "All of the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A shared lock allows which of the following types of transactions to occur?", "opta": "Delete", "optb": "Insert", "optc": "Read", "optd": "Update", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Locking may cause which of the following problems?", "opta": "Erroneous updates", "optb": "Deadlock", "optc": "Versioning", "optd": "All of the above.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Performance analysis and tuning is which of the following?", "opta": "Undertaken one time at the time of a DBMS installation", "optb": "Undertaken one time at the time of the implementation of a new application", "optc": "Undertaken as an ongoing part of the backup of a database", "optd": "Undertaken as an ongoing part of managing a database", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is the preferred way to recover a database after a transaction in progress terminates abnormally?", "opta": "Rollback", "optb": "Rollforward", "optc": "Switch to duplicate database", "optd": "Reprocess transactions", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is true concerning open-source DBMS?", "opta": "Is free or nearly free database software whose source code is publicly available", "optb": "Is free or nearly free database software whose source code is not publicly available", "optc": "Is not competitive against PC-oriented packages and is fully SQL compliant", "optd": "Is competitive against PC-oriented packages and is not fully SQL compliant", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Concurrency control is important for which of the following reasons?", "opta": "To ensure data integrity when updates occur to the database in a multiuser environment", "optb": "To ensure data integrity when updates occur to the database in a single-user environment", "optc": "To ensure data integrity while reading data occurs to the database in a multiuser environment", "optd": "To ensure data integrity while reading data occurs to the database in a single-user environment", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is the preferred way to recover a database after a system failure?", "opta": "Rollback", "optb": "Rollforward", "optc": "Switch to duplicate database", "optd": "Reprocess transactions", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A data warehouse administrator is concerned with which of the following?", "opta": "The time to make a decision but not the typical roles of a database administrator", "optb": "The time to make a decision and the typical roles of a database administrator", "optc": "The typical roles of a data administrator and redesigning existing applications", "optd": "The typical roles of a database administrator and redesigning existing applications", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}